## SM Mashuque

347-694-9301

sm2344@cornell.edu

smmashuq.com

linkedin.com/in/smmashuq

### **PROFILE**

Determined to become a Software Engineer. I am always excited to build things with programming. I have experience working with APIs and Django framework from last internship. Learning new things about software design is very exciting to me. I am always exploring and expanding my understanding of important concepts and best practices in programming. I want to keep learning and develop my understanding of various ideas in software architecture and web scalability. So far, my experience has been more about working with back-end technologies, but I do have interest in learning about front-end technologies.

### **EDUCATION**

## Cornell University, B.S.

05/2020

- Cumulative GPA: 3.3
- Major in Information Science. Minor in Computer Science.
- Relevant courses taken include OO Programming in Python, Data Science in Python, Data Structures in Java, Backend Web Development in PHP, and Systems Programming in C/C++.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Teaching Assistant in INFO/CS 2300: Backend Web Design 08/2018 to 12/2018

Cornell University

- Helped students with questions relating to server side data processing and creating dynamic pages using HTML, PHP, and database.
- Met with professor weekly and helped grade assignments.

## Teaching Assistant in INFO/CS 1300: Intro Web Design 08/2018 to 12/2018

Cornell University

- Helped students with questions relating to HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in the intro web design course.
- Met with professor weekly and helped grade assignments.

Software Engineer Intern 06/2018 to 08/2018

SinglePlatform

- Django MVC: Updated existing models, views, templates, and wrote unit tests.
- Created an API endpoint with pagination for restaurant locations, menus, and photos data using Django REST framework.
- Created asynchronous tasks to update models, and send emails using Celery and SendGrid.
- Applied view restrictions with Python decorators.
- Created a GUI app in Python for internal use to automate schedule creation process using Google Calendar API

### Python Tutor

08/2017 to 05/2018

### Cornell University

 Met with CS 1110 course students weekly and provided assistance with Python questions relating to homework, assignments, and exams.

#### SKILLS

D3.js

<b>Programming Languages</b>	
Python	
Java	
С	
C++	
JavaScript	
PHP	
Databases	
PostgreSQL	
SQLite	
Redis	
Frameworks	
Django	
Angular	
Libraries	
NumPy	
React	
jQuery	